

CONTACT

(+33) 7 88 07 84 13 antarikshashrivastavafs@ gmail.com Portfolio Website linkedin.com/in/antariksha Paris, 75012, France

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Office Suit:

Word, Excel, PowerPoint

Coding:

Python, SQL, Java, C/C++, HTML/CSS3

Data Driven Tools:

Google Analytics, Data Studio, Tableau, Power BI, Dataiku

SOFT SKILLS

Analytical, Communication, Team player, Result oriented-problem solver, Critical Thinking , Customer oriented

LANGUAGES

- English (Professional Working)
- French (Elementary)

AWARDS

Faculty Award for outstanding contribution to organization and role model to colleagues- TCS

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Volunteered for Teaching at school in Pune. Mar 2018—Aug 2020
- Organized an event Dream Jabalpur held at GGITS. Sep 2014

HOBBIES

Playing Cricket, Listening to Music, watching movies, Visiting museums and gallery, Traveling, Programming

ANTARIKSHA SHRIVASTAVA

DATA ANALYST

Experienced data analyst with 4 years' work experience in a multinational IT company. Trained in Python and SQL for large-scale data analysis. Passionate and eager to learn more about how data can be collected and analyzed to create real business impact. Looking for an end-of-studies internship starting from July 2021. No visa assistance required in future for France.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SYSTEM ENGINEER

Jan 2017 — Sep 2020

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES, INDIA

Worked as data analyst on multiple projects with different clients including Jaguar & Land Rover, Lafarge Holcim, Atos and Bank of America.

Jaguar & Land Rover

- Data collection on company operations (Google Analytics, Excel).
- Identified appropriate areas where Machine Learning applications could be more powerful and profitable.
- Delivered several business insights extracted from raw data, mining to identify and perform meaningful analysis.

Lafarge Holcim

- Built and maintained dashboards for clients based on their requirements (Tableau).
- Contributed in planning, implementation and integration of system- oriented projects with different stakeholders.
- Mentored 5 junior system engineers across multiple projects.

ASSISTANT SYSTEM ENGINEER

Oct 2016 — Dec 2016

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES, INDIA

- Mastered MS-Excel, Python, Java and acquired technical knowledge on data science techniques.
- Cleaned, analyzed, modelled, and interpreted data by working on multiple projects.
- Created data visualization and marketing dashboards in Tableau.

EDUCATION

MSc IN DIGITAL MARKETING & DATA SCIENCE

Sep 2020 — Mar 2022

EMLYON BUSINESS SCHOOL, PARIS

Python Coding and Text Mining +Excel and SQL +Data Visualization
Machine Learning +CRM Data Platforms +AI in Marketing

Projects:

- Airbnb rental quality Dashboard in New York City using POWER BI
- Analysis of Employee Performance Tableau.
- Predicting House Prices in France using Multiple Linear Regression.

B.E IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Jun 2012 — Jun 2016

Rajiv Gandhi Proudyogiki Vishwavidyalaya, INDIA

- Studied the concepts of Java, C++, Hadoop, SDLC, Mathematics, Software Engineering and Project Management, Data Structures, Object Oriented Programming, Operating Systems, Database Management Systems.
- Member of Computer Society of India (CSI)

CERTIFICATIONS

➤ Data Analysis with Python – IBM

➤ Google Analytics- Google Academy

➤ Intermediate Python – Datacamp

➤ Intermediate SQL- Datacamp

➤ Introduction to Data Science in Python- Datacamp